Miguel Gomez

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER student

miguelgomez66@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | Portfolio |

SUMMARY

Professional habits person, with more than 15 years of experience in the Oil&Gas market and becoming a Full Stack developer at Microverse. Enjoying new challenges such as training employees and organizing the dispatch of a gas producer or automating tasks mixing electronics and apps development.

SKILLS

Front-End: React/Redux, Rails, HTML5, CSS3

Back-End: Ruby

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring **Electronics**: Arduino based hobby projects to control systems via SMS

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS
Full Stack Web Developer

Remote January 2021- Present

MERN social app — Full-stack MERN social app.

- Built with: React, nodeJS, MongoDB
- For web or mobile

<u>Telegram bot</u> — Telegram bot to present the weather forecast for the user using GPS location or custom query.

- Built with: Ruby
- For web or mobile

<u>Physical Activity Logger</u> — App for having fun and compete with family or friends logging how much time you spent exercising, grouping the activities into categories.

Built with: RoR, Postgres

<u>2D Spaceship Game</u> — Old style game for spending time collecting energy pills and avoiding enemies.

• Built with: Javascript, Phaser 3

Natural gas-related companies in Argentina (Gasnor, Garmarket, ENARSA, Camuzzi Gas)

Position Title

July 200

Argentina

July 2005 - November, 2020

- Led the natural gas dispatch team of brokers and producers.
- Coordinated the dispatch team and focused on negotiating with customers for maximizing incomes.
- Generated new businesses using the distribution company and the broker company resources.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE

January 2021 - Present

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

CERTIFICATIONS

Microsoft Office Specialist Excel 2016 Expert • Microsoft Credential ID